In brightest day. In blackest night.
Green Lantern is a adventure, action, thriller film directed by Martin Campbell.
For centuries, a small but powerful force of warriors called the Green
Lantern Corps has sworn to keep intergalactic order.
Each Green Lantern wears a ring that grants him superpowers.
But when a new enemy called Parallax threatens to destroy the balance of power in the Universe,
their fate and the fate of Earth lie in the hands of the first human ever recruited.
Hal Jordan / Green Lantern, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Carol Ferris, played by Blake Lively.
Hector Hammond, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Sinestro, played by Mark Strong.
Senator Hammond, played by Tim Robbins.
Dr. Amanda Waller, played by Angela Bassett.
Green Lantern is a 2011 American superhero film
based on the character from DC Comics.
It was directed by Martin Campbell, from a screenplay by Greg Berlanti,
Michael Green, Marc Guggenheim, and Michael Goldenberg.
Ryan Reynolds stars as Hal Jordan / Green Lantern, a test pilot who is selected to become the
first human member of the Green Lantern Corps, an intergalactic police force.
He is given a ring that grants him superpowers and must confront Parallax, a
being who threatens to upset the balance of power in the universe.
The film also stars Blake Lively, Peter Sarsgaard, Mark
Strong, Angela Bassett, and Tim Robbins.
The film first entered development in 1997; progress remained stalled
until Berlanti was hired to write and direct in October 2007.
Martin Campbell was brought on board in February 2009 after
Berlanti was forced to vacate the director's position.
Most of the live-action actors were cast between July 2009 and February 2010,
and filming took place from March to August 2010 in Louisiana.
The film was converted to 3D during its post-production stage.
This was the first DC film since Catwoman (2004) not to
be involved with Legendary Pictures.
Green Lantern was released in the United States
on June 17, 2011, by Warner Bros.
The film received negative reviews from critics, with criticism for the direction, script, tone, visual
effects, humor, and unfaithfulness to the source material, though Reynolds' performance was praised.
It grossed only $220 million against a $200 million budget.
Intended to start a media franchise and shared universe
based on DC characters, Warner Bros.
scrapped the plans due to the film's critical and commercial disappointment; instead using Man
of Steel (2013) as the first film of the DC Extended Universe two years later.
The film explores themes of superhero, transformation,
based on comic, alien, alien infection.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.